<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Databases on Documentation for our Projects and Web Handbook</title><link>/webhandbook/databases/</link><description>Recent content in Databases on Documentation for our Projects and Web Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/webhandbook/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/webhandbook/databases/_2_/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/databases/_2_/</guid><description>SQL databases SQL stands for structured query language and is used for querying relational databases. Relational databases derive from the idea of simple tables. Every row in the table is then called a dataset or tuple; its columns hold the so-called attributes of the datasets. Relations between tables can be expressed by using the same identifier (ID) or a combination of attributes for a dataset in different tables, this is also referred to as a key.</description></item><item><title/><link>/webhandbook/databases/_3_/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/databases/_3_/</guid><description>NoSQL databases Web services that operate in real time and process diverse datasets pose a challenge when it comes to storage (Kaufmann and Meier, 2019). In these cases, NoSQL databases can provide a solution: They are easily scalable, allow fast querying and are said to make work for developers easier (Schaefer, 2021). Unlike what one might expect, the “No” in NoSQL stands for “not only”.
The rigid structures of traditional relational databases can be limiting for certain kinds of data and sometimes not all features of relational databases are needed (Lai, 2009).</description></item><item><title>1 Functionalities of databases in web applications</title><link>/webhandbook/databases/_1_/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/databases/_1_/</guid><description>Interacting with a web application means sending requests to a server which then retrieves data to display. The server will also handle new data that is created while using the application as well as alterations on the existing data. Since these tasks can become quite complex, the server itself is not the optimal place to handle them. Therefore, elaborate operations on data and displaying dynamic data should be performed by a suitable database software (Williams and Lane, 2006).</description></item></channel></rss>