<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>authentication on Documentation for our Projects and Web Handbook</title><link>/tags/authentication/</link><description>Recent content in authentication on Documentation for our Projects and Web Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/tags/authentication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. What is authentication and why do we need it?</title><link>/webhandbook/authentication/_1_what_is_authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/authentication/_1_what_is_authentication/</guid><description>Authentication is the process of determining whether someone is who they say they are by checking to see if their credentials match the credentials in a database of authorized users. It is an important aspect of the security of a system and prevents unauthorized users from accessing sensitive data. It is even featured in the OWASP Top Ten Web Application Security Risks as ‘Identification and Authentication Failures’ in the 2021 version.</description></item><item><title>2. Types of authentication</title><link>/webhandbook/authentication/_2_types_of_authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/authentication/_2_types_of_authentication/</guid><description>A username or ID which is unique for each user is always required to determine their identity. If a client claims a specific identity, proof is required. Depending on the kind of proof that is required, authentication can be divided into three types: something you know, something you have, and something you are.
The most commonly used type of authentication would be a password, which makes it something that you know.</description></item><item><title>3. Authentication methods on the web</title><link>/webhandbook/authentication/_3_authentication_methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/authentication/_3_authentication_methods/</guid><description>After an authentication type has been chosen, the next step is to determine what method of authentication on the web will be used. When a website is using server side rendering, the client is in constant communication with the webserver, sending a request each time a resource is needed. Each of those request needs a proof of authentication to make sure sensitive data cannot be accessed by unauthorized user. Instead of making the user authenticate themselves for each request to the server, there are different ways to store and communicate the credentials safely with the server.</description></item><item><title>4. Conclusion</title><link>/webhandbook/authentication/_4_conclusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/authentication/_4_conclusion/</guid><description>As mentioned before, OWASP lists identification and authentication failures in its top 10 web security risks. This shows just how critical it is to implement proper authentication for a webapp to improve security. They also offer some advice on how prevent this security risk and possible attack scenarios on their website.
Simple password-based authentication is mostly used for webapps. It is easy to implement due to extensive documentation and code examples on the web.</description></item><item><title>5. Sources</title><link>/webhandbook/authentication/_5_sources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/authentication/_5_sources/</guid><description>Authentication (last accessed January 8, 2022): https://www.techtarget.com/searchsecurity/definition/authentication
Identification and Authentication Failures (last accessed January 9, 2022): https://owasp.org/Top10/A07_2021-Identification_and_Authentication_Failures/
What Is Certificate-Based Authentication and Why Should I Use It? (last accessed on January 8, 2022): https://www.globalsign.com/en/blog/what-is-certificate-based-authentication
5 Authentication Methods that Can Prevent the Next Breach (last accessed January 9, 2022): https://www.idrnd.ai/5-authentication-methods-that-can-prevent-the-next-breach/
The Ultimate Authentication Playbook (last accessed January 9, 2022): https://www.okta.com/blog/2019/02/the-ultimate-authentication-playbook/
Web Authentication Methods Compared (last accessed January 9, 2022): https://testdriven.io/blog/web-authentication-methods/
Authentication for web applications (last accessed January 9, 2022): http://web.</description></item></channel></rss>