<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chapter on Documentation for our Projects and Web Handbook</title><link>/tags/chapter/</link><description>Recent content in chapter on Documentation for our Projects and Web Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/tags/chapter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>APIs</title><link>/webhandbook/apis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/apis/</guid><description>APIs Einleitungstext</description></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>/webhandbook/authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/authentication/</guid><description>Authentication Authentication is the process of determining whether someone or something is, in fact, who or what they say they are. A big part of the security of a web application is therefore to verify the identity and credentials of a user accessing the system. This helps preventing unauthorized users from accessing sensitive data.
These credentials usually consist of a username and password. Different types of authentication such as 2-factor authentication, multiple factor authentication or certificate-based authentication offer different ways to authenticate oneself.</description></item><item><title>CI/CD</title><link>/webhandbook/ci_cd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/ci_cd/</guid><description>CI: CONTINUOUS INTEGRATION / CD: CONTINUOUS DELIVERY PIPELINE CI ist eine Abkürzung für Continuous Integration, was auf Deutsch kontinuierliche In- tegration bedeutet. Dieser Vorgang ermöglicht es den Mitgliedern eines Teams, kontinu- ierlich neue Codes in einem bestimmten Repository zu speichern. Dann dieser Datenmen- ge führt CI automatisch Tests durch und prüft die Fehlerfreiheit. Gleichzeitig unterstützt es die Softwareentwicklung, indem es Fehler schneller meldet und Lösungen anbietet. Folgende Schritte werden als Pipeline bezeichnet: Der Programmierer lädt den Code in das Repository hoch.</description></item><item><title>CSS Processing</title><link>/webhandbook/css_processing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/css_processing/</guid><description>CSS Processing CSS is a powerful styling language whose feature set is constantly evolving, that allows incredible flexibility when designing websites. However, maintaining the structure, compatibility, and efficiency of stylesheets can become problematic, especially as projects grow.
Various CSS processing tools aim to address the shortcomings of the language with different approaches. Either by adding features to the language, modifying the syntax, or optimizing already written CSS. Of course, Browsers only understand the spec-compliant official version of CSS, so whatever a processor is doing has to happen before the client evaluates the CSS stylesheet.</description></item><item><title>Databases</title><link>/webhandbook/databases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/databases/</guid><description>Databases in Web Applications Databases are a crucial part of every web application as they are the place where all information processing happens. To choose the right database for an application, it is necessary to look closely at the use case and the data to store. This chapter will firstly illustrate in detail which functions have to be fulfilled by a web application database. It will then highlight the main features of SQL databases and will shortly present MySQL, PostgreSQL and MariaDB as examples hereof.</description></item><item><title>Microservices</title><link>/webhandbook/microservices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/microservices/</guid><description>Microservices Einleitungstext</description></item><item><title>Node.js</title><link>/webhandbook/node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/node/</guid><description>Node.js Einleitungstext</description></item><item><title>React</title><link>/webhandbook/react/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/react/</guid><description>React Einleitungstext</description></item><item><title>UI/UX</title><link>/webhandbook/ui_ux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/ui_ux/</guid><description>UI/UX Einleitungstext</description></item><item><title>Vergleich verschiedener Programmiersprachen mit Fokus auf Web-Technology</title><link>/webhandbook/programming_languages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/programming_languages/</guid><description>Vergleich verschiedener Programmiersprachen mit Fokus auf Web-Technology Im folgenden Text geht es um den Vergleich verschiedener Web-Programmiersprachen. Zunächst werden dabei die Grundlagen der Typisierung und Typsicherheit sowie Backend und Frontend näher erläutert. Anschließend werden insgesamt 5 Programmiersprachen näher vorgestellt, wobei besonders die Punkte Typisierung, Typsicherheit, objektorientierte Programmierung sowie die Anwendung im Front- und Backend-Bereich der einzelnen Programmiersprachen im Fokus liegen. Aufgrund des begrenzten Umfangs dieses Textes werden folgende Web-Programmiersprachen vorgestellt: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, PHP und Ruby.</description></item><item><title>Web Frameworks</title><link>/webhandbook/web_frameworks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/web_frameworks/</guid><description>Web Frameworks Einleitungstext</description></item><item><title>Website Rendering</title><link>/webhandbook/website_rendering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/webhandbook/website_rendering/</guid><description>Contents of this Chapter Fundamentals of Website Rendering Types of Render Modes and their Advantages and Disadvantages A Visual Guide on when to use which Rendering Mode Sources</description></item></channel></rss>